Nashville, TN | 641-204-1133

ABOUT ME

The thing that drew me to data science was the collaborative environment, data narrative story-telling, and a chance to work with numbers. As a STEM major, I graduated college with the choice of academia or industry. Choosing neither, I worked for a glasses start up where I got to wear many different hats. I tried on the data exploration hat and found that it fit really well. After some research, I found out that Nashville Software School had a program committed entirely to data science. Combining people skills and numbers is a rare find, and I'm excited to further my data science knowledge by working with a diverse, talented group of people.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Data Science Bootcamp | 2021

Mississippi College

Bachelors of Science in Chemistry (ACS) cum laude

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python (pandas, GeoPandas, Folium, Plotly, NumPy, Seaborn, RegEx, BeautifulSoup, scikit-learn)
- R Tidyverse, Shiny, Dashboard, Plotly
- PostgreSQL
- Machine Learning (scikit-learn, under-sampling, SMOTE

EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School | Data Science Apprenticeship | September 2020-Present

Nashville Software School's Data Science bootcamp utilizes hands-on experience and group projects to learn python and pandas, R Shiny, R tidyverse, SQL, and machine learning.

- Big G Express Trucking data (group):
 - Using diagnostic, fault, and datetime data to predict if a truck will derate within a specific timeframe
 - Python pandas, scikit-learn logistic regression, imblearn under-sampling & SMOTE
- COVID violations and cluster tracking in Nashville (group):
 - o Looking at Nashville companies' COVID violations, COVID clustering data, and Nashville geospatial data.
 - Python pandas, geospatial, and plotly in Jupyter Notebooks
- People3: Diversity and Inclusion (group):
 - o Comparing a company's employee diversity to the company's city census data via an R Shiny app
 - o R Shiny, dashboard, tidyverse, plotly, and US census data
- <u>Climate Change</u> (independent):
 - Tracking down multiple data sources to tell a story of climate change's impact on human life via an R Shiny App
 - R Shiny app using R plotly, tidyverse, and shiny
- Provider Communities in Nashville (group):
 - o Gaining insight into Nashville's healthcare referral scene using Medicare data built into a Google Site
 - Python pandas, SQLite, plotly, and Google Sites

Warby Parker | October 2016-August 2020

Warby Parker is an eyeglasses and contacts startup based in New York and Nashville.

- Order Processing Team Lead | October 2018-August 2020
 - Quality assurance, process documentation, people management
- Customer Experience | October 2016-October 2018